远古以前，一个遥远的星系...
银河参议会掀起一场骚动
数千个星系纷纷表达...
退出共和国的意图
分离主义运动...
在神秘的杜酷伯爵带领下...
逐渐脱离绝地武士的掌握
银河的和平秩序面临失控
艾米达拉参议员，前那卜女王
正赶往银河参议会
为重大议案投下一票
决定是否建立共和军
协助寡不敌众的绝地武士
参议员，我们即将抵达科罗森
Senator, we're making our final approach into Coruscant.
很好，队长
Very good, Lieutenant.
成功安全抵达
We made it.
看来是我错了
I guess I was wrong.
似乎根本没有危险
There was no danger at all.
柯笛...
Corde.
殿下...很抱歉
Milady, I'm so sorry.
我未能完成使命，参议员
I've failed you, Senator.
不
No.
殿下，此处尚有危险
Milady, you're still in danger here.
我根本不该回来
- I shouldn't have come back. - This vote is very important.
这次投票很重要，你尽忠职守 柯笛鞠躬尽瘁了，走吧
You did your duty. Corde did hers. Now, come.
艾米达拉议员，请
Senator Amidala, please.
我没把握投票还能拖延多久
I don't know how much longer I can hold off the vote, my friends.
越来越多星系投入分离主义
More and more star systems are joining the separatists.
一旦他们脱离...
If they do break away--
我不会坐视共和国...
I will not let this Republic that has stood for a thousand years...
屹立千年之后竟一分为二
be split in two.
我的协商不会破裂
My negotiations will not fail.
万一协商不成，你了解...
If they do, you must realize...
绝地武士不足以保护共和国
there aren't enough Jedi to protect the Republic.
我们是和平保护者，不是军人
We're keepers of the peace, not soldiers.
尤达大师...
Master Yoda...
你认为真的会有战争吗？
do you think it will really come to war?
黑暗势力无孔不入
The dark side clouds everything.
无法看清未来之事
Impossible to see the future is.
皇家委员已抵达，阁下
The Loyalist Committee has arrived, Your Honor.
很好
Good.
请他们进来
Send them in.
此事稍后再讨论
We will discuss this matter later.
艾米达拉参议员...
Senator Amidala, your tragedy on the landing platform--
登陆台上的悲剧让人遗憾
terrible.
你的平安让我十分宽心
Seeing you alive brings warm feelings to my heart.
你们知不知道是谁指使的？
Do you have any idea who was behind this attack?
我们的情报显示是...
Our intelligence points to disgruntled
那卜星不满的香料矿工所为
spice miners on the moons of Naboo.
我认为是杜酷伯爵策动的
I think that Count Dooku was behind it.
他是政治理想家，不是杀人魔
He is a political idealist, not a murderer.
殿下，杜酷伯爵曾是绝地武士
You know, milady, Count Dooku was once a Jedi.
他不可能从事暗杀
He couldn't assassinate anyone.
他的人格不允许他这么做
It's not in his character.
确定的是，参议员...
But for certain, Senator...
你的处境极为危险
in grave danger you are.
绝地大师，容我建议安排...
MasterJedi, may I suggest...
参议员接受你们的保护
the senator be placed under the protection of your graces?
明智吗？时局如此紧张之际
Do you really think that's a wise decision under these stressful times?
议长阁下，我不相信...
Chancellor, if I may comment, I do not believe--
...时局...真有如此严重
The situation is that serious?
不，但我认为，参议员...
No, but I do, Senator.
我了解额外的保全...
I realize all too well that additional security...
会对你造成困扰，但...
might be disruptive for you...
或许我能指派个熟人...
but perhaps someone you're familiar with.
老朋友，比如说肯诺比大师
An old friend, like Master Kenobi.
颇为可行
That's possible.
他刚调解完昂逊星的疆界纠纷
He's just returned from a border dispute on Ansion.
请给我个面子，殿下
Do it for me, milady. Please?
万一失去你
The thought of losing you...
我将无法忍受
is unbearable.
我请欧比王立刻向你报到
I will have Obi-Wan report to you immediately, milady.
谢谢你，云杜大师
Thank you, Master Windu.
你好像很紧张
- You seem a little on edge.
一点也不
- Not at all.
从误陷钢鞑巢穴后...
I haven't felt you this tense since
没看过你这么紧张
we fell into that nest of gundarks.
是你深陷险境，师父
You fell into that nightmare, Master...
我救了你，记得吗？
and I rescued you, remember?
对啦
Oh... yes.
你在冒汗，放轻松，深呼吸
You're sweating. Relax. Take a deep breath.
跟她已经十年不见了
I haven't seen her in ten years, Master.
欧比？欧比！好高兴见到你！
Obi? Obi!- Mesa so smilen to seein yousa!
很高兴又见面，恰恰
- Good to see you again,JarJar.
帕米参议员！
Senator Padme.
我朋友来了，你看，参议员
Mesa palos here! Lookie, lookie, Senator.
绝地武士到了
Desa Jedi arriven.
很荣幸再见面，殿下
It's a great pleasure to see you again, milady.
时光飞逝啊，肯诺比大师
It has been far too long, Master Kenobi.
安纳？
Ani?
天啊，你长大了
- My goodness, you've grown.
你也是啊
- So have you.
我是说，你更漂亮了
Grown more beautiful, I mean.
以参议员的标准来说
Well, for a senator, I mean.
对我你永远是塔图印的小男孩
Ani, you'll always be that little boy I knew on Tatooine.
我承诺你不会感到我们的存在
Our presence here will be invisible, milady, I can assure you.
泰佛队长，陛下的护卫
I'm Captain Typho of Her Majesty's security service.
亚蜜莉雅女王已得知这项指派
Queen Jamillia has been informed of your assignment.
很高兴你能来
I am grateful you are here, Master Kenobi.
局势比参议员所知的更险恶
The situation is more dangerous than the senator will admit.
我需要答案，不是加强警戒
I don't need more security. I need answers.
我要知道谁想杀我
I want to know who's trying to kill me.
我们是来保护你，不是来调查
We are here to protect you, Senator, not to start an investigation.
我们会查出谁想杀你，帕米...
We will find out who's trying to kill you, Padme. I promise you.
我们不会逾越职权，小徒弟
We will not exceed our mandate, my young Padawan learner.
我只是说尽力保护她，师父
I meant that in the interest of protecting her, Master, of course.
别再跟我争辩，安纳金
We will not go through this exercise again, Anakin...
多听从我的教诲
and you will pay attention to my lead.
为什么？
- Why?
什么？
- What?
派我们来为什么不调查凶手？
Why else do you think we were assigned to her if not to find the killer?
保护工作是本地警方的任务
Protection is a job
派绝地武士等于杀鸡用牛刀
for local security, notJedi.
所以调查权隐含在我们职权内
It's overkill, Master. Investigation is implied in our mandate.
我们遵守议长的指示就是了
We will do exactly as the council has instructed.
学著恪遵本分，年轻人
And you will learn your place, young one.
你们的出现就显得事有蹊跷了
Perhaps with merely your presence... the mystery surrounding this threat will be revealed.
若不介意...容我告退
Now, if you'll excuse me... I will retire.
你们留在这里让我放心多了
I know I'll feel better having you here.
我会在每层楼都派驻军官
I'll have an officer stationed on every floor...
我本人在楼下指挥中心
and I'll be in the control center downstairs.
真高兴又见面了，安纳
Mesa busten wit happiness seein yousa again, Ani.
她几乎不认识我了，恰恰
She hardly even recognized me,JarJar.
她走后我天天思念她
I've thought about her every day since we parted and...
她却把我忘得一干二净
she's forgotten me completely.
她很快乐，比以前还快乐
Shesa happy. Happier den mesa seein her in a longo time.
你尽往坏处想，当心你的思想
You're focusing on the negative, Anakin. Be mindful of your thoughts.
刚见面时她十分开心
She was pleased to see us.
去检查一下安全措施
Now, let's check the security.
击中了太空船，但他们用替身
I hit the ship, but they used a decoy.
要用更巧妙的手段，婵姆
We'll have to try something more subtle this time, Zam.
我的客户快失去耐性了
My client is getting impatient.
拿去，小心有毒
Take these. Be careful. They're very poisonous.
婵姆，这次不能再出错了
And, Zam, there can be no mistakes this time.
泰佛队长派很多人驻扎楼下
Captain Typho has more than enough men downstairs.
刺客不会从那里进来
No assassin would try that way.
上面有动静吗？
- Any activity up here?
一片死寂
- Quiet as a tomb.
我不喜欢枯等
I don't like just waiting here for something to happen to her.
怎么回事？
- What's going on? - She covered the cameras.
摄影机遮住了，她不想让我看
I don't think she liked me watching her.
她心里在想什么？
What is she thinking?
有入侵者R2会警告我们
She programmed R2 to warn us if there is an intruder.
刺杀参议员的方法不仅只如此
There are many other ways to kill a senator.
我知道，我们也想抓刺客吧？
I know, but we also want to catch this assassin, don't we, Master?
你把她当成饵？
You're using her as bait.
那是她的主意
It was her idea.
别担心，她不会受到任何伤害
Don't worry. No harm will come to her.
我可以感觉她房内的一举一动
I can sense everything going on in that room.
相信我
Trust me.
风险太高
It's too risky.
再说，你的感觉还不够协调
Besides, your senses aren't that attuned, my young apprentice.
你的就够协调？
And yours are?
可以这么说
Possibly.
你很累了
You look tired.
我再也睡不安稳
I don't sleep well anymore.
因为你的母亲？
Because of your mother?
不晓得为什么一直梦见她
I don't know why I keep dreaming about her.
梦境随时间消逝
Dreams pass in time.
我宁可梦见帕米
I'd much rather dream about Padme.
待在她身边就令人脸红心跳
Just being around her again is... intoxicating.
当心你的思绪，它会背叛你
Be mindful of your thoughts, Anakin. They betray you.
你承诺过要信守绝地武士诫律
You've made a commitment to theJedi order... a commitment not easily broken.
她是政治人物，不值得信赖
And don't forget, she's a politician. They're not to be trusted.
她跟其他议员不一样
She's not like the others in the senate, Master.
根据我的经验，议员们...
It is my experience that senators focus...
只讨好赞助自己政治主张的人
only on pleasing those who fund their campaigns...
为获得赞助往往不顾民主真义
and they're in no means scared of forgetting the niceties of democracy...
不要再说教了
- in order to get those funds. - Not another lecture.
至少不要谈政客的黑金问题
At least not on the economics of politics.
而且你是以偏概全
And besides, you're generalizing.
议长不像个贪官感吏
The chancellor doesn't appear to be corrupt.
白卜庭是个政客
Palpatine is a politician.
他是个聪明人
I have observed that he is very clever...
深谙投各议员所好的巧妙手腕
in following the passions and the prejudices of the senators.
我认为他是个好人，师...
I think he's a good man--
我也感觉到了
I sense it too.
留在这里！
Stay here!
您没事吧？
Are you all right, milady?
搞什么？
What the--
怎么这么慢？
- What took you so long? - Oh, you know, Master.
找不到中意的飞艇... 他在那里
- I couldn't find a speeder I liked... - There he is.
...要敞蓬座舱，速度又要快
with the open cockpit and the right speed capabilities.
你要是多练光剑少练嘴皮子
If you spent as long practicing your saber techniques as you do your wit...
剑术大概可以直逼尤达大师了
you would rival Master Yoda as a swordsman.
我已经跟他不相上下了
I thought I already did.
别一厢情愿，小徒弟
Only in your mind, my very young apprentice.
拉起来，安纳金，拉起来！
Pull up, Anakin. Pull up!
我不喜欢你乱耍花招
You know I don't like it when you do that.
抱歉师父，忘了你不喜欢飞行
Sorry, Master. I forgot you don't like flying.
飞行还好，你刚刚是自杀！
I don't mind flying, but what you're doing is suicide!
跟你说过多少次...
Anakin! How many times have I told you...
不要穿越电藕火花
stay away from power couplings!
得到教训了吧
That was good!
你要去哪？他往那边去了！
Where are you going? He went that way.
继续追下去，那怪胎会被烧焦
Master, if we keep this chase going any longer... that creep is gonna end up deep-fried...
我想查出他是谁？谁派来的？
and, personally, I'd like to find out who he is and who he's working for.
这是捷径...我认为
This is a shortcut... I think.
好啦，跟丢了
Well, you've lost him.
非常抱歉，师父
I'm deeply sorry, Master.
好个捷径，他根本往另一边走
That was some shortcut, Anakin. He went completely the other way.
再一次证明你...
- Once again you've proved--
失陪一下
- If you'll excuse me.
可恶，他又来这套
I hate it when he does that.
安纳金！
Anakin!
她逃进俱乐部里了，师父
- She went into the club, Master. - Patience.
耐心，使用原力，思考
- Use the Force. Think.
对不起，师父
- Sorry, Master.
他是躲进去，不是从那逃走
- He went in there to hide, not to run.
是的，师父
- Yes, Master.
下次不要乱丢
- Next time, try not to lose it.
是的，师父
- Yes, Master.
这武器是你的生命
- This weapon is your life.
我尽量记住，师父
- I try, Master.
老感觉总有一天我会被你害死
Why do I get the feeling you're going to be the death of me?
别这么说，我把你当成父亲
Don't say that, Master. You're the closest thing I have to a father.
那你怎么老是不听话？
Then why don't you listen to me?
我正在努力
I am trying.
看到他了吗？
Can you see him?
我认为他是个女的
I think he is a she...
而且她会变身
and I think she is a changeling.
这么说，要格外小心
In that case, be extra careful.
去找她
- Go and find her.
你要去哪里？
- Where are you going, Master?
喝一杯
For a drink.
谢谢
Thank you.
要不要买点销魂棒？
-You wanna buy some death sticks?
不要向我兜售销魂棒
-You don't want to sell me death sticks.
我不向你兜售销魂棒
I don't want to sell you death sticks.
回家思考生命的意义
You want to go home and rethink your life.
我要回家思考生命的意义
I want to go home and rethink my life.
没事
Easy.
绝地武士任务，继续喝
Jedi business. Go back to your drinks.
你知道你刺杀的是谁吗？
Do you know who it was you were trying to kill?
那卜星的参议员
It was a senator from Naboo.
谁雇你的？
- And who hired you?
只不过是出趟任务
- It was just a job.
谁雇你的？说
Who hired you? Tell us.
快说！
Tell us now!
一位赏金猎人，叫...
It was a bounty hunter called--
毒镖
Toxic dart.
查出这个赏金猎人，欧比王
Track down this bounty hunter you must, Obi-Wan.
更重要的是查出谁在主使
Most importantly, find out who he's working for.
艾米达拉议员还需要保护吗？
What about Senator Amidala? She will still need protecting.
你徒弟会去执行
Handle that your Padawan will.
安纳金，保护参议员回那卜星
Anakin, escort the senator back to her home planet of Naboo.
她在那儿比较安全
She'll be safer there. And don't use registered transport.
别搭乘公共运输，乔装成难民
Travel as refugees.
身为反对阵营领袖
As the leader of the opposition, it will be very difficult...
她不太容易离开首都
to get Senator Amidala to leave the capital.
逮到杀手前...
Until caught this killer is...
她必须遵守我们的裁定
our judgment she must respect.
安纳金，到参议院去
Anakin, go to the senate...
要求白卜庭议长找她谈谈
and ask Chancellor Palpatine to speak with her about this matter.
我跟她沟通，艾米达拉议员...
I will talk with her.
不会违抗我的命令
Senator Amidala will not refuse an executive order.
我跟她很熟，不会有问题
I know her well enough to assure you of that.
谢谢您，阁下
Thank you, Your Excellency.
他们终于派任务给你了
And so, they've finally given you an assignment.
你的耐心有了代价
Your patience has paid off.
你的指导功用更胜于我的耐心
Your guidance more than my patience.
你不需要人指导，安纳金
You don't need guidance, Anakin.
你很快将学会相信自己的感觉
In time, you will learn to trust your feelings.
然后你就所向无敌了
Then you will be invincible.
我说过很多次
I have said it many times:
你是最有天赋的绝地武士
You are the most gifted Jedi I have ever met.
多谢褒奖，阁下
Thank you, Your Excellency.
你会成为最伟大的绝地武士
I see you becoming the greatest of all theJedi, Anakin...
力量更胜于尤达大师
even more powerful than Master Yoda.
我很替我徒弟担心
I am concerned for my Padawan.
他还不适合接派任务
He is not ready to be given this assignment on his own yet.
议会对其决定有信心
The council is confident in its decision, Obi-Wan.
那男孩有过人的才能
The boy has exceptional skills.
但他还有很多要学
But he still has much to learn, Master.
他的能力使得他...傲慢自大
His abilities have made him, well, arrogant.
对，绝地武士日益普遍的缺点
Yes. A flaw more and more common among Jedi.
太自以为是
Too sure of themselves they are.
甚至老一辈有经验的也一样
Even the older, more experienced ones.
记住，欧比王，若预言成真...
Remember, Obi-Wan, if the prophecy is true...
只有安纳金能让原力重归和谐
your apprentice is the only one who can bring the Force back into balance.
我要请一段长假
I'm taking an extended leave of absence.
你得在参议院代理我的职务
It will be your responsibility to take my place in the senate.
冰克斯代表...全靠你啦
Representative Binks, I know I can count on you.
很荣幸担此重任
Mesa honored to be taking on dissa heavy burden.
我十分谦虚的接受任务
Mesa accept this with muy, muy humility and--
恰恰，我不耽搁你的时间
JarJar, I don't wish to hold you up.
你还有很多工作要做
I'm sure you have a great deal to do.
那当然...殿下
Of course. Milady.
我不喜欢躲躲藏藏
I do not like this idea of hiding.
别担心，议会已下令调查
Don't worry. Now that the council has ordered an investigation...
欧比王大师会找出那赏金猎人
it won't take Master Obi-Wan long to find this bounty hunter.
我努力一整年对抗建军案
I haven't worked for a year to defeat the Military Creation Act...
事到临头竟无法投票
to not be here when its fate is decided.
有时得将自尊摆一边听命行事
Sometimes we must let go of our pride... and do what is requested of us.
安纳金...你成熟多了
Anakin, you've grown up.
欧比王却极力视而不见
Master Obi-Wan manages not to see it.
别误会，欧比王是个好老师
Don't get me wrong. Obi-Wan is a great mentor.
他智慧可比尤达大师
As wise as Master Yoda and...
力量不输云杜大师
as powerful as Master Windu.
我很感激他收我为徒
I am truly thankful to be his apprentice.
但在某些方面...许多方面...
In some ways-- a lot of ways--
我已经青出于蓝
I'm really ahead of him.
我已经准备好接受试验
I'm ready for the trials...
但他觉得我难以捉摸
but he feels that I'm too unpredictable.
不让我更上一层楼
He won't let me move on.
你一定感到很挫折 比挫折还糟！
- That must be frustrating. - It's worse.
他百般挑剔，从不听我说
He's overly critical. He never listens.
他不了解我，这不公平！
He doesn't understand. It's not fair!
师父比我们更容易看清缺点
All mentors have a way of seeing more of our faults than we would like.
我们就是这样成长的
It's the only way we grow.
我了解
I know.
安纳金...不要急著长大
Anakin... don't try to grow up too fast.
但我已经长大了
But I am grown up.
你自己也这么说过
You said it yourself.
不要这样看我
Please don't look at me like that.
为什么？
Why not?
看得我浑身不自在
It makes me feel uncomfortable.
对不起，殿下
Sorry, milady.
保重，殿下
- Be safe, milady.
谢谢你，队长
- Thank you, Captain.
多照顾朵美，威胁转向你们了
Take good care of Dorme. The threat's on you two now.
他跟我在一起很安全
He'll be safe with me.
你不会有事的
You'll be fine.
问题不在我，我担心的是你
It's not me, milady. I worry about you.
万一他们知道你离开首都呢？
What if they realize you've left the capital?
我的保护者就得秀出真本事了
Well, then myJedi protector will have to prove how good he is.
安纳金，采取任何行动前...
Anakin...
先询问我或议会的意见
don't do anything without first consulting either myself or the council.
是的，师父
Yes, Master.
我会查清楚这项阴谋
I'll get to the bottom of this plot quickly, milady.
你很快就可以再回来
You'll be back here in no time.
非常感谢你迅速查案
I'll be most grateful for your speed, MasterJedi.
该走了
- It's time to go.
我知道
- I know.
安纳金，愿原力与你同在
Anakin, may the Force be with you.
愿原力与你同在，师父
May the Force be with you, Master.
我突然感到害怕
Suddenly I'm afraid.
这是我第一次单独出任务
This is my first assignment on my own.
我也会害怕
I am too.
不用担心，有R2在
Don't worry. We have R2 with us.
我希望他不会轻举妄动
I do hope he doesn't try anything foolish.
我反而比较担心她会轻举妄动
I'd be more concerned about her doing something than him.
亲爱的，有人来找你
Someone to see ya, honey!
看起来是个绝地武士
Jedi, by the looks of him.
欧比王！
Obi-Wan!
哈啰，德克斯
Hello, Dex.
坐一下，我马上过来
Take a seat. I'll be right with ya.
来一杯夹哇果汁吧
- You wanna cup o'jawa juice?
好啊，谢谢
- Oh, yes. Thank you.
嘿...老哥！
Old buddy!
老朋友，我能帮什么忙？
So, my friend, what can I do for ya?
这是什么东西？
You can tell me what this is.
很久没见到这玩意，自从...
Well, whattaya know!
在外星系外的萨特罗采矿之后
I ain't seen one of these since I was prospectin'...
on Subterrel, beyond the outer rim.
它从哪里来的？
Can you tell me where it came from?
这是复制人的东西
This baby belongs to them cloners.
这支是卡密诺星的剑镖
What you got here is a Kamino saberdart.
档案资料库里没有这东西
I wonder why it didn't show up in the analysis archives.
看镖身的特殊切割就知道
It's these funny little cuts on the side that give it away.
“分析机器人”只会看标志
Those analysis droids only focus on symbols.
你们绝地武士应该多注重...
I should think that you Jedi would have more respect...
知识与智慧的区别
for the difference between knowledge and... wisdom.
机器人会思考，我们还混什么
Well, if droids could think... there'd be none of us here, would there?
我不了解卡密诺星
Kamino. I'm not familiar with it.
它是共和国的一员吗？
Is it in the Republic?
不，它在外星系之外
No, no. It's beyond the outer rim.
在厘希迈司外约12秒差的距离
I'd say about 1 2 parsecs outside the Rishi Maze.
连资料库机器人都不难找到它
Should be easy to find, even for those droids in your archives.
卡密诺人...离群索居
These Kaminoans keep to themselves.
他们是复制人，非常优异
They're cloners. Damn good ones too.
这些复制人友善吗？
- Cloners. Are they friendly?
视情况而定
- Depends.
视什么情况，德克斯？
Depends on what, Dex?
视你的态度以及...
On how good your manners are...
你口袋里的钞票而定
and how big your... pocketbook is.
是你要求协助的吗？
- Did you call for assistance?
是的
- Yes, I did.
有问题吗，肯诺比大师？
Are you having a problem, Master Kenobi?
我想找卡密诺行星系统... 卡密诺？
Yes, I'm looking for a planetary system called Kamino.
但不在档案图库里面
It doesn't show up on the archive charts.
我对卡密诺星系不熟
Kamino. It's not a system I'm familiar with.
你座标没弄错吧？
Are you sure you have the right coordinates?
根据资料，应该在这个象限里
According to my information, it should appear in this quadrant here...
紧临厘希迈司南边
just south of the Rishi Maze.
你寻找的星系似乎不存在
I hate to say it, but it looks like the system you're searching for... doesn't exist.
不可能，除非档案资料不完整
Impossible. Perhaps the archives are incomplete.
档案里没有就一定不存在
If an item does not appear in our records... it does not exist.
你！不招待机器人，出去！
Hey, you! No droids! Get outta here!
谢谢你，R2
Thank you, R2.
绝地武士的生活一定相当清苦
Must be difficult, having sworn your life to theJedi...
行动、行事都受到限制
not being able to visit the places you like or do the things you like.
也不能跟所爱的人在一起
Or be with the people that I love.
你可以爱人吗？
Are you allowed to love?
我以为绝地武士是不准动情的
I thought that was forbidden for a Jedi.
不得爱恋
Attachment is forbidden.
不得拥有
Possession is forbidden.
慈悲心...我定义成无私的爱...
Compassion, which I would define as unconditional love...
是绝地武士的中心思想
is central to a Jedi's life.
所以可以解释为...“爱心广被”
So you might say that we are encouraged to love.
你变好多
You've changed so much.
你一点都没变
You haven't changed a bit.
跟我梦中的你一模一样
You're exactly the way I remember you in my dreams.
探索，感受周遭的原力
Reach out. Sense the Force around you.
一定要运用你的感觉
Use your feelings you must.
年轻人！年轻人！
Younglings. Younglings!
有客人来访
A visitor we have.
哈啰，欧比王大师
Hello, Master Obi-Wan.
抱歉打扰，大师
Hello. I'm sorry to disturb you, Master.
有何指教，欧比王？
What help can I be, Obi-Wan?
我在找一个老朋友介绍的行星
I'm looking for a planet described to me by an old friend.
但该星系不在档案地图里
I trust him, but the systems don't show on the archive maps.
欧比王找不到一颗行星，真糗
Lost a planet Master Obi-Wan has.
真糗啊！连恩，拉上窗帘
How embarrassing! Liam, the shades.
围在地图仪四周
Gather round the map reader.
清理你们的思绪
Clear your minds...
我们就会找到欧比王要的行星
and find Obi-Wan's wayward planet we will.
它应该在...这里，但却找不到
It ought to be here... but it isn't.
这区的重力将星球都吸往这点
Gravity is pulling all the stars in the area towards this spot.
重力作用存在，但所有星体...
Gravity's silhouette remains... but the star and all the planets...
却消失无踪
disappeared they have.
怎么会这样？想想看？
How can this be? A thought?
谁有答案？
Anyone.
大师
Master?
有人在记忆体里将它清除掉
Because someone erased it from the archive memory.
这孩子果然聪明
Truly wonderful the mind of a child is.
这小徒弟说对了
The Padawan is right.
前往重力作用的中心点
Go to the center of gravity's pull...
你就会找到你要的行星
and find your planet you will.
资料一定是被删除了
The data must have been erased.
可是，尤达大师
But who could empty information
谁做的？不太可能，不是吗？
from the archives? Isn't that impossible?
的确是危机重重、疑云密布
Dangerous and disturbing this puzzle is.
删除者必定是位绝地武士
Only a Jedi could have erased those files.
谁？为什么？则更难回答
But who and why, harder to answer.
让我好好沉思一番
Meditate on this I will.
我并非最年轻的民选女王
I wasn't the youngest queen ever elected...
但现在回想起来
but now that I think back on it, I'm not sure I was old enough.
可能真的太年轻，不够有把握
I'm not sure I was ready.
你的同胞认为你很称职
The people you served thought you did a good job.
为了让你续任还企图修订宪法
I heard they even tried to amend the constitution... so you could stay in office.
两任届满后终于得以退休
I was relieved when my two terms were up.
但继任女王要我当参议员
But when the queen asked me to serve as senator...
我实在无法拒绝
I couldn't refuse her.
我赞同她，共和国需要你
I agree with her. I think the Republic needs you.
很高兴你继续为国服务
I'm glad that you chose to serve.
参议院若同意建军会引发内战
If the senate votes to create an army, it's sure to push us into a civil war.
不敢想像
It's unthinkable!
共和国成立后未曾有过战争
There hasn't been a full-scale war since the formation of the Republic.
和谈不能挽回分离主义者吗？
Do you see any way through negotiations... to bring the separatists back into the Republic?
除非感受到威胁不然不会同意
Not if they feel threatened.
我想他们会向贸易联盟
They'll turn to the Trade Federations
或商业协会求救
or the Commerce Guilds for help.
可耻，最高法院已四度审判...
It's outrageous... but after four trials in the Supreme Court...
纽特甘雷仍稳坐贸易联盟总督
Nute Gunray is still the viceroy of the Trade Federation.
恐怕参议院无力解决此次危机
I fear the senate is powerless to resolve this crisis.
对共和国要有信心
We must keep our faith in the Republic.
丧失民主信心就是失败的到来
The day we stop believing democracy can work is the day we lose it.
希望这天永远不会来
Let's pray that day never comes.
同时，我们也得顾虑你的安全
In the meantime, we must consider your own safety.
你有何建议，绝地大师？
What is your suggestion, MasterJedi?
安纳金还不是绝地武士
Anakin's not a Jedi yet.
他还在学徒阶段，我认为...
He's still a Padawan learner.
等一下
- But I was thinking-- - Hold on a minute.
抱歉，我想我该待在千湖区
Excuse me. I was thinking I would stay in the lake country.
那里有些地方非常隐密
There are some places up there that are very isolated.
抱歉！安全问题由我负责
Excuse me. I'm in charge of security here, milady.
这里是我的故乡，我清楚
And this is my home. I know it very well.
这也是为什么我们要回来
That is why we're here.
此事最好善用我的知识
I think it would be wise... if you took advantage of my knowledge in this instance.
对不起，殿下
Sorry, milady.
很好，就这么决定
Perfect. It's settled, then.
在那儿，R4
There it is, R4, right where it should be.
正处于它失踪的位置...卡密诺
Our missing planet Kamino.
绝地大师
MasterJedi.
首相恭候大驾光临
The prime minister is expecting you.
等我？
- I'm expected?
当然
- Of course.
他急著见你呢
He is anxious to meet you.
经过这么多年后...
After all these years...
我们以为你不会来了，这边请
we were beginning to think you weren't coming. Now, please, this way.
容我引见拉玛苏
May I present Lama Su...
卡密诺的首相
prime minister of Kamino.
这位是绝地大师...
And this is MasterJedi--
欧比王肯诺比
Obi-Wan Kenobi.
希望你感到不虚此行
I trust you're going to enjoy your stay.
请坐，我们来谈正事吧
Please. And now to business.
你一定很高兴进度完全正常
You will be delighted to hear that we are on schedule.
已完成20万单位
200,000 units are ready...
另有一百万个正在生产中
with a million more well on the way.
真是...好消息
That's good news.
请转告西佛迪雅大师...
Please tell your Master Sifo-Dyas...
他的订单我们会准时交货
that his order will be met on time.
对不起...哪位大师？
I'm sorry. Master--
绝地大师西佛迪雅还是...
Jedi Master Sifo-Dyas is still...
绝地议会的首席，不是吗？
a leading member of theJedi Council, is he not?
西佛迪雅大师十年前就遇害了
Master Sifo-Dyas was killed almost ten years ago.
哦，我深感遗憾
I'm so sorry to hear that.
他一定会因为我为他...
But I'm sure he would have been proud of the army
建造的军队感到骄傲
we've built for him.
军队？
The army?
是的，复制人大军
Yes, a clone army, and I must say...
可以说我们所造最精良的一批
one of the finest we've ever created.
我们大师订制这支部队时...
Tell me, Prime Minister... when my master first contacted you about the army...
曾说明用途吗？
did he say who it was for?
当然有
Of course he did.
是要供共和国使用的
This army is for the Republic.
但你一定急著亲自点阅
But you must be anxious to inspect the units for yourself.
正是我此行的目的
That's why I'm here.
学生时代常来此地静修
We used to come here for school retreat.
每天游到那个小岛
We would swim to that island every day.
我很喜欢这里的水
I love the water.
躺在沙滩上作日光浴
We used to lie out on the sand and let the sun dry us...
猜爱唱歌鸟儿的名字
and try to guess the names of the birds singing.
我不喜欢沙子
I don't like sand.
又粗又乱使人过敏...
It's coarse and rough and irritating...
还沾得到处是
and it gets everywhere.
不像这里
Not like here.
到处都很柔软...光滑
Here, everything is soft... and smooth.
不行，我不该这么做
No. I shouldn't have done that.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真壮观
Very impressive.
我想你会满意
I'd hoped you would be pleased.
复制人具思考能力
Clones can think creatively.
你会发现他们比机器人好很多
You will find that they are immensely superior to droids.
战斗教育和训练课程...
We take great pride in our combat education
也令我们相当自傲
and training programs.
这一组是五年前开发出来的
This group was created about five years ago.
你刚提过加速成长
You mentioned growth acceleration.
那是必要的，不然...
Oh, yes, it's essential.
要等一辈子，复制人才能成熟
Otherwise, a mature clone would take a lifetime to grow.
现在只需要一半时间
Now we can do it in half the time.
我明白了
I see.
绝对服从，绝不怀疑命令
They are totally obedient... taking any order without question.
我们做了些基因改造...
We modified their genetic structure...
让他们比母体较不具独立性
to make them less independent than the original host.
他们的原始母体是谁？
And who was the original host?
赏金猎人强格费特
A bounty hunter called Jango Fett.
他现在在哪里？
And where is this bounty hunter now?
我们将他留在此地
Oh, we keep him here.
除了巨额酬庸...
Apart from his pay, which is considerable...
费特只要求一件事
Fett demanded only one thing:
为他保留一个未改造的复制人
an unaltered clone for himself.
奇怪吧？
- Curious, isn't it?
未改造？
- ''Unaltered''?
纯正基因的复制品
Pure genetic replication.
基因未曾驯化成较温和
No tampering with the structure to make it more docile...
而且也不经加速成长处理
and no growth acceleration.
我想见见这位强格费特
I should very much like to meet this Jango Fett.
非常乐意为你安排
I would be very happy to arrange it for you.
壮观吧？
Magnificent, aren't they?
我不知道
I don't know.
你当然知道，只是不跟我说
Sure you do. You just don't want to tell me.
你要用绝地念力控制我？
You gonna use one of your Jedi mind tricks on me?
那只对心智虚弱者有效
They only work on the weak-minded.
好吧
All right.
我当时12岁，他叫帕罗
I was 1 2. His name was Palo.
我们参加青少年立法训练营
We were both in the Legislative Youth Program.
他比我大几岁，很可爱
He was a few years older than I. Very cute.
黑色卷发，迷蒙的眼神
Dark, curly hair. Dreamy eyes.
好，我有概念了
All right, I get the picture.
他后来怎么了？
Whatever happened to him?
我从事公共服务，他当艺术家
I went into public service. He went on to become an artist.
或许他比较聪明
Maybe he was the smart one.
你真的不喜欢政治人物？
You really don't like politicians, do you?
有二、三个喜欢的...
I like two or three...
但有一个我还不太清楚
but I'm not really sure about one of them.
我不觉得政府体系有任何功效
I don't think the system works.
你认为怎么样才有功效？
How would you have it work?
政治人物应该坐下来讨论问题
We need a system where the politicians sit down and discuss the problem...
根据人民的最高福祉去做
agree what's in the best interest of all the people... and then do it.
这正是我们的做法
That's exactly what we do.
问题是，人民不会永远同意
The trouble is that people don't always agree.
应该说服他们
Well, then they should be made to.
谁去说服？
- By whom? Who's gonna make them?
我怎么知道...某人
- I don't know. Someone.
你？
- You?
当然不
- Of course not me.
但一定有某个人
- But someone.
某个有智慧的人
- Someone wise.
听起来颇像独裁政权
Sounds an awful lot like a dictatorship to me.
只要是具有功效
Well, if it works.
你在开我玩笑
- You're making fun of me. - No.
我可不敢捉弄参议员大人
I'd be much too frightened to tease a senator.
安纳？你还好吧？
Ani, are you all right?
波巴，你父亲在吗？
Boba, is your father here?
在
Yep.
可以见他吗？
May we see him?
当然
Sure.
爸，道维来找你
Dad, Taun We's here.
强格，欢迎回来
Jango, welcome back.
这趟旅行收获丰富吗？
Was your trip productive?
还好
Fairly.
这位是绝地大师欧比王肯诺比
This is Jedi Master Obi-Wan Kenobi.
他来视察进度的
He's come to check on our progress.
你的复制人很棒
Your clones are very impressive.
你一定感到相当骄傲
You must be very proud.
只是在宇宙中混口饭吃
I'm just a simple man trying to make my way in the universe.
你曾经到过科罗森吗？
Ever made your way as far into the interior as Coruscant?
一、二次吧
- Once or twice.
最近呢？
- Recently?
有可能
Possibly.
那你一定认识西佛迪雅大师
Then you must know Master Sifo-Dyas.
波巴，把门关上
Boba, rood eht so-heeck.
哪位大师？
Master who?
西佛迪雅
Sifo-Dyas.
不是他聘雇你做这项工作吗？
Is he not theJedi who hired you for this job?
没听说过他
Never heard of him.
真的？
Really?
柏格登卫星的提拉诺斯聘我的
I was recruited by a man called Tyranus on one of the moons of Bogden.
奇怪
Curious.
军队你还满意吗？
Do you like your army?
我想看他们的战斗表现
I look forward to seeing them in action.
骁勇善战，我保证
They'll do their job well. I'll guarantee that.
多谢接见，强格
Thank you for your time,Jango.
我一向乐于接待绝地武士
Always a pleasure to meet a Jedi.
怎么回事，爸？
What is it, Dad?
收拾行李，我们得离开
Pack your things. We're leaving.
找到他们后，我们...
And when I got to them,
激烈的争辩一番
we went into aggressive negotiations.
谢谢
怎么个“激烈的争辩”？
''Aggressive negotiations''? What's that?
呃...用光剑争辩
Well, negotiations with a lightsaber.
如果被欧比王看到我这样做
If Master Obi-Wan caught me doing this,
他会抓狂
he'd be very grumpy.
自从与你相识...
From the moment I met you...
...好多年以前的事了...
all those years ago...
我没有一天不想你
not a day has gone by when I haven't thought of you.
今天再度与你相遇...
And now that I'm with you again...
我反而觉得很痛苦
I'm in agony.
越接近你就越痛苦
The closer I get to you, the worse it gets.
一想到不能跟你在一起...
The thought of not being with you--
连气都快喘不过来
I can't breathe.
我仍被你的吻迷惑著
I'm haunted by the kiss...
你不该吻我的
that you should never have given me.
我内心惴惴不安...
My heart is beating...
希望它不会变成爱的伤痕
hoping that that kiss will not become a scar.
你在我灵魂深处，折磨著我
You are in my very soul... tormenting me.
我该怎么办呢？
What can I do?
只要你说，我一定照做
I will do anything that you ask.
如果你跟我一样深受折磨...
If you are suffering as much as I am,
请你说出来
please, tell me.
我不能说
I can't.
我们不能在一起，不可能的
We can't. It's...just not possible.
什么事都有可能，听我说...
Anything is possible, Padme. Listen to me.
不，你听我说
No, you listen.
我们活在现实世界，醒来吧
We live in a real world. Come back to it.
你专心学习当绝地武士...
You're studying to become a Jedi.
我当我的参议员
I'm a senator.
跟著你的感觉走下去的话...
If you follow your thoughts through to conclusion...
只会走到无法收拾的地步...
it'll take us to a place we cannot go...
不管我们对彼此有什么感觉
regardless of the way we feel about each other.
这么说，你也有感觉
Then you do feel something.
我不会让你为我放弃前途
I will not let you give up your future for me.
你要我保持理智
You are asking me to be rational.
这一点我做不到
That is something I know I cannot do.
但愿我能忘却这份感情...
Believe me, I wish that I could just wish away my feelings...
但我做不到
but I can't.
我不会儿女情长的
I will not give in to this.
你知道吗...
Well, you know...
事情不一定非这样不可
it wouldn't have to be that way.
我们可以偷偷相爱
We could keep it a secret.
那我们必须活在谎言中
We'd be living a lie...
纸是包不住火的
one we couldn't keep even if we wanted to.
我不能这么做
I couldn't do that.
你可以吗？过那种日子？
Could you, Anakin? Could you live like that?
不可以，你说得对
No. You're right.
我们会被毁了
It would destroy us.
告诉议会，第一支军队备妥了
Tell your council that the first battalions are ready.
提醒他们，如果需要更多军队
And remind them, if they need more troops...
将需要更多时间培育他们
it will take more time to grow them.
谨记在心，多谢
I won't forget, and thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
R4！
R4!
用第5密码加密传讯到科罗森
Scramble code five to Coruscant,
收件人写“养老院”
care of the old folks' home!
我跟卡密诺首相碰过面
I have successfully made contact with the prime minister of Kamino.
他们用赏金猎人强格费特...
They are using a bounty hunter named
作为母体制造一支复制人大军
Jango Fett to create a clone army.
我觉得这位赏金猎人就是刺客
I have a strong feeling that this bounty hunter... is the assassin we are looking for.
你认为订制复制人的人...
Do you think these cloners are involved...
跟刺杀阴谋有关？
in the plot to assassinate Senator Amidala?
不，大师，似乎无此动机
No, Master. There appears to be no motive.
不要假设，欧比王
Do not assume anything, Obi-Wan.
一定要先清除杂念...
Clear your mind must be...
如果你想查出幕后的主谋
if you are to discover the real villains behind this plot.
是的，大师，他们说...
Yes, Master.
复制人是西佛迪雅大师订制的
They say Master Sifo-Dyas placed an order for a clone army...
根据十年前参议院的要求
at the request of the senate almost ten years ago.
印象中，他在那之前已遇害
I was under the impression he was killed before that.
绝地议会有授权订制复制人？
Did the council ever authorize the creation of a clone army?
没有，不管订制者是谁
No. Whoever placed that order...
绝地议会并未授权
did not have the authorization of theJedi Council.
带他来，我们当面对质
Bring him here. Question him we will.
是的，找到他后再行报告
Yes, Master. I will report back when I have him.
我们真是盲目啊...
Blind we are if creation of this clone army...
竟然不知复制人悄悄在生产
we could not see.
我们得通知参议院，我们...
I think it is time we informed the senate...
运用原力的能力已大为减弱
that our ability to use the Force has diminished.
只有西斯的黑暗大帝...
Only the dark lord of the Sith
明明白我们的弱点
knows of our weakness.
通知参议院...
If informed the senate is...
只会让我们的处境更加窘迫
multiply our adversaries will.
不
No.
妈...不...不要！
Mom, no.
不要走
Don't go.
我不想打扰你
I don't want to disturb you.
你的出现有安抚作用
Your presence is soothing.
你昨晚又作恶梦了
You had another nightmare last night.
绝地武士不会作恶梦
Jedi don't have nightmares.
我听见了
I heard you.
我梦见我的母亲
I saw my mother.
她正受著苦，帕米
She is suffering, Padme.
见到她跟见到你一样清晰
I saw her as clearly as I see you now.
她很痛苦
She is in pain.
我知道这会违抗保护你的命令
I know I'm disobeying my mandate to protect you, Senator...
但，我得去一趟
but I have to go.
我必须去救她
I have to help her.
我跟你一起去
I'll go with you.
很抱歉，我别无选择
I'm sorry. I don't have a choice.
爸！你看！
Dad, look!
波巴，快上船！
Boba, get on board!
不妙
Oh, not good.
在这里等著
Wait right there.
好
Okey-okey.
你好，瓦头
Chut-chut, Watto.
我来帮你忙
Let me help you with that.
什么？你想干嘛？
What? What do you want?
等等，你是绝地武士
Wait! You're a Jedi!
不管是什么问题，不是我干的
Whatever it is, I didn't do it.
我来找西蜜天行者
I'm looking for Shmi Skywalker.
安纳？小安纳？
Ani? Little Ani?
是安纳！真的是你！
You are Ani! It is you!
长好高了
You sure sprouted, huh?
绝地武士！真是个惊喜
AJedi! Whattaya know!
或许可以帮我催收些烂帐
Maybe you could help with some deadbeats who owe me a lot of money.
我母亲呢？
My mother.
哦，对了，西蜜
Oh, yeah. Shmi.
她不归我了，我将她卖了
She's not mine-a no more-a. I sold her.
卖了？
- You sold her?
很多年了
- Years ago.
抱歉，安纳，生意归生意
Sorry, Ani, but you know, business is business.
卖给个水气收集农夫，叫拉斯
I sold her to a moisture farmer named Lars.
我记得应该是拉斯
At least I think it was Lars.
信不信由你，听说...
Believe it or not, I heard
他给她自由并跟她结婚了！
he freed her and married her!
想不到有这种好事吧
Can ya beat that, eh?
知不知道他们现在在哪？
Do you know where they are now?
离这儿很远
Long way from here.
应该在摩斯艾斯里港的那头吧
Someplace over on the other side of Mos Eisley, I think.
我想知道
I'd like to know.
没问题，当然！
Sure. Absolutely!
去查查我的记录
Let's go look at my records, huh?
爸！我们被盯梢了！
Dad! I think we're being tracked!
一定有追踪器粘在我们船身上
He must have put a homing device on our hull.
坐好，我们将进入小行星群里
Hang on, son. We'll move into the asteroid field...
让他开开眼界
and we'll have a couple of surprises for him.
震碎炮待命
Seismic charges! Stand by.
他好像还是不懂我的意思
He doesn't seem to take a hint, this guy.
小心！
Watch out!
干掉他，爸！干掉他！
Get him, Dad!
发射！
Fire!
要命！我真恨飞行
Blast! This is why I hate flying!
打中了！
We got him!
再给他致命的一击
We'll just have to finish him.
R4，准备抛弃备用零件
R4, prepare to jettison the spare part canisters.
抛射！
Fire them now!
再也不会见面了
We won't be seeing him again.
R4，我们等得够久了
Well, R4, I think we've waited long enough.
联盟船舰不寻常的在此集结
There's an unusual concentration of Federation ships over there, R4.
在此留守，R2
Stay with the ship, R2.
哈啰，需要效劳吗？我是C...
Hello. How might I be of service? I am C--
3PO？
3PO?
创造者！噢，安纳主人！
The maker! Master Ani!
我就知道你会回来！
I knew you would return. I knew it!
还有帕米小姐，噢，天啊
And Miss Padme. Oh, my.
哈啰，3PO
Hello, 3PO.
上苍保佑，真高兴见到二位
Bless my circuits! I'm so pleased to see you both.
我来找我母亲的
I've come to see my mother.
我们进去屋里吧
I think perhaps we'd better go indoors.
欧文主人，为你介绍两位贵客
Master Owen, might I present two most important visitors.
我是安纳金天行者
I'm Anakin Skywalker.
欧文拉斯，我女朋友蓓鲁
Owen Lars. - This is my girlfriend, Beru. - Hello.
我叫帕米
I'm Padme.
我应该是你的同母异父弟弟吧
I guess I'm your stepbrother.
我一直感觉有一天你会来
I had a feeling you might show up someday.
我母亲在吗？
Is my mother here?
不，她不在
No, she's not.
克里格拉斯，西蜜是我太太
Cliegg Lars. Shmi is my wife.
我们进去
We should go inside.
有很多事情该谈谈
We have a lot to talk about.
就在黎明前夕
It was just before dawn. They came out of nowhere.
突然冒出一群塔斯肯强盗
A hunting party ofTusken Raiders.
你母亲照例一大早起来...
Your mother had gone out early, like she always did...
采收凝结器上的蘑菇
to pick mushrooms that grow on the vaporators.
从足迹看来，她回到半路上...
From the tracks, she was about halfway home...
却被掳走了
when they took her.
塔斯肯族走路像人，可是...
Those Tuskens walk like men...
他们很凶恶... 是冷酷的怪物
but they're vicious, mindless monsters.
30人前去营救，只有4人回来
Thirty of us went out after her. Four of us came back.
我也想去，可是腿断了后...
I'd be out there with them, but after I lost my leg...
无法驾驶
I just couldn't ride anymore
只好等痊愈再想办法
until I heal.
我不会放弃搜救
I don't want to give up on her...
只是她失踪几个月了
but she's been gone a month.
活存那么久的机会不大
There's little hope she's lasted this long.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
去找我母亲
To find my mother.
你母亲死了，接受事实吧
Your mother's dead, son. Accept it.
你留在这里
You're gonna have to stay here.
他们是好人，没有危险
These are good people, Padme. You'll be safe.
安纳金...
Anakin
我很快就回来
I won't be long.
商业协会和企业联盟必须签约
We must persuade the Commerce Guild... and the Corporate Alliance to sign the treaty.
那卜星的参议员怎么对付？
What about the senator from Naboo?
她还没死吗？
Is she dead yet?
除非看到她的头，否则我不签
I am not signing your treaty until I have her head on my desk.
我以信誉保证，总督
I am a man of my word, Viceroy.
有了我们打造的战斗机器人...
With these new battle droids we've built for you...
你拥有全银河最精良的部队
you'll have the finest army in the galaxy.
正如我先前解释过的...
As I explained to you earlier...
又将有一万多个星系...
I am quite convinced that 1 0,000 more systems...
加入我们的行动...
will rally to our cause
只要你们肯支持
with your support, gentlemen.
你的提议可被视为叛国罪
What you are proposing could be construed as treason.
科技联邦的机器人...
The Techno Union army...
...悉听您的差遣，伯爵
is at your disposal, Count.
银行公会愿意签署条约
The Banking Clan will sign your treaty.
好，很好
Good. Very good.
贸易联盟的朋友们已誓言支持
Our friends from the Trade Federation have pledged their support...
他们的战斗机器人加上你们的
and when their battle droids are combined with yours...
我们将拥有银河最强大的军队
we shall have an army greater than any in the galaxy.
绝地武士根本不是对手
TheJedi will be overwhelmed.
共和国将任凭我们宰割
The Republic will agree to any demands we make.
妈？妈？
Mom?
安纳
Ani?
安纳...是你吗？
Ani? Is it you?
我来找你了，妈
I'm here, Mom.
你安全了
You're safe.
安纳？
Ani?
你长得好帅
You look so handsome.
我的儿子...
My son.
我长大成人的儿子
My grown-up son.
我以你为荣，安纳
I'm so proud of you, Ani.
我好想你
I missed you.
我死而无憾了
Now I am complete.
我爱你...
I love y--
不要丢下我，妈
Stay with me, Mom.
一切...
Everything--
我爱...
I love--
我...爱...
安纳金！安纳金！
Anakin!
不！
No!
怎么回事？
What is it?
痛苦...挣扎...
Pain, suffering...
...死亡，我感觉到了
death I feel.
恐怖的事发生了
Something terrible has happened.
年少天行者遭逢苦难
Young Skywalker is in pain...
极大的痛苦
terrible pain.
传输器没故障，但毫无回音
The transmitter is working, but we're not receiving a return signal.
科罗森太远，能加强功率吗？
Coruscant's too far. R4, can you boost the power?
我们得另外想办法
We'll have to try something else.
尝试连络在那卜星的安纳金
Maybe we can contact Anakin on Naboo.
那儿近多了
It's much closer.
安纳金？听得到吗？
Anakin, do you copy?
我是欧比王，安纳金？
This is Obi-Wan Kenobi. Anakin?
他不在那卜星上，R4
He's not on Naboo, R4.
我试试加大频宽
I'm going to try and widen the range.
希望他没出什么乱子
I do hope nothing's happened to him.
那是安纳金的追踪讯号
That's Anakin's tracking signal, all right...
但它来自塔图印
but it's coming from Tatooine.
他去那里干什么？
What in the blazes is he doing there?
跟他说过好好待在那卜星
I told him to stay on Naboo.
我们没有什么时间
We haven't got much time.
安纳金，听到吗？我是欧比王
Anakin, do you copy? This is Obi-Wan Kenobi.
重新传输讯息
Retransmit this message--
安纳金？听得到吗？安纳金？
Anakin, do you copy?
我的长程...故障
My long-range transmitter has been knocked out.
本将讯息转传至科罗森
Retransmit this message to Coruscant.
吃点东西吗？
I brought you something.
饿不饿？
Are you hungry?
排档杆坏了
The shifter broke.
修东西时生活显得单纯多了
Life seems so much simpler when you're fixing things.
我对修理东西很在行
I'm good at fixing things. Always was.
一向如此，但我不能...
But I couldn't--
为什么她非死不可？
Why'd she have to die?
为什么我救不了她？我可以的
Why couldn't I save her? I know I could have!
有时候天命难违
Sometimes there are things no one can fix.
你无法拥有无上的力量，安纳
- You're not all-powerful, Ani.
我应该可以的
- Well, I should be!
有一天我一定可以
Someday I will be.
我会成为史上最强的绝地武士
I will be the most powerfulJedi ever.
我说到做到
I promise you.
甚至学会让人长生不老
I will even learn to stop people from dying.
安纳金
Anakin
都是欧比王的错
It's all Obi-Wan's fault!
他嫉妒我！
He's jealous!
他阻碍我进步
He's holding me back!
怎么回事，安纳金？
What's wrong, Ani?
我杀了他们
I killed them.
我把他们全杀了
I killed them all.
他们都死了
They're dead.
一个都不留活口
Every single one of them.
不只是男人...
And not just the men...
连妇女和小孩无一幸免
but the women... and the children too.
他们跟野兽没什么两样！
They're like animals...
我像杀野兽一样宰了他们！
and I slaughtered them like animals!
我恨他们！
I hate them!
你这么愤怒是很正常的
To be angry is to be human.
但我是绝地武士
I'm a Jedi.
我知道我应该要看破一切
I know I'm better than this.
我知道，不管你在哪里...
I know wherever you are
那个地方都会变得更美好
it's become a better place.
你是男人一生中...
You were the most loving partner
最难得的可爱伴侣
a man could ever have.
再见了，亲爱的妻子
Good-bye, my darling wife.
也谢谢你
And thank you.
我不够强，没救到你，妈
I wasn't strong enough to save you, Mom.
我还不够强
I wasn't strong enough.
但我发誓...
But I promise
我以后不会再失败
I won't fail again.
我想你，我好想你
I miss you... so much.
R2，有什么事？
R2? What are you doing here?
它好像收到一个叫...
It seems that he is carrying
欧比王肯诺比传来的讯息
a message from an Obi-Wan Kenobi.
安纳主人，听过这名字吗？
Master Ani, does that name mean anything to you?
长程传输器故障
Anakin, my long-range transmitter has been knocked out.
我将讯息转传至科罗森
Retransmit this message to Coruscant.
我跟随赏金猎人强格费特...
I have tracked the bounty hunter, Jango Fett...
来到机器人生产地吉诺西斯
to the droid foundries on Geonosis.
贸易联盟到此点收机器人军队
The Trade Federation is to take delivery of a droid army here...
很明显甘雷总督...
and it is clear that Viceroy Gunray...
是行刺艾米达拉议员的主谋
is behind the assassination attempts on Senator Amidala.
商业协会和企业联盟...
The Commerce Guilds and the Corporate Alliance...
双双带兵投靠杜酷伯爵
have both pledged their armies to Count Dooku and are forming--
形成...等一下
Wait.
吉诺西斯进行著的阴谋...
More happening on Geonosis, I feel,
远比我们所知的严重
than has been revealed.
我同意，安纳金...
I agree.
我们会对付杜酷
We will deal with Count Dooku.
你一定要留在目前的所在地
The most important thing for you is to stay where you are.
尽全力保护参议员
Protect the senator at all costs.
这是你的首要之务
That is your first priority.
我懂，大师
Understood, Master.
他们无法及时赶过去
They'll never get there in time to save him.
他们远在银河的另一边
They have to come halfway across the galaxy.
你看，吉诺西斯...
Look.Geonosis
离我们不到一秒差的距离
is less than a parsec away.
那是假设如果他还活著的话
If he's still alive.
你就坐视他面临死亡？
Are you just gonna sit here and let him die?
他是你朋友，你...
- He's your friend, your mentor.
他有如我的父亲！
- He's like my father!
但云杜大师命我留在此地！
But you heard Master Windu. He gave me strict orders to stay here.
他命令你保护我
He gave you strict orders to protect me...
而我要前去协助欧比王
and I'm going to help Obi-Wan.
要保护我就跟我一起去
If you plan to protect me, you'll just have to come along.
我不担心，R2，只是我没飞过
I'm not worried, R2. It's just I've never flown before.
商业协会正在备战
The Commerce Guilds are preparing for war. There can be no doubt of that.
杜酷一定跟他们签署了条约
Count Dooku must have made a treaty with them.
辩论终结！
The debate is over.
我们需要复制人军队
Now we need that clone army.
可惜，辩论还没终结
Unfortunately, the debate is not over.
分离主义者攻击前...
The senate will never approve the use of clones...
参议院不会同意使用复制人
before the separatists attack.
这是重大危机！参议院应该...
This is a crisis.
投票赋予议长紧急处分权
The senate must vote the chancellor emergency powers.
然后他有权同意建军
He can then approve the creation of an army.
但哪位参议员有这个胆子...
But what senator would have the courage...
敢提出这种激进的修正案？
to propose such a radical amendment?
如果艾米达拉议员在就好了
If only Senator Amidala were here.
叛徒！
Traitor.
不，我的朋友，你错了
Oh, no, my friend. This is a mistake, a terrible mistake.
他们做得太过分了
They have gone too far.
简直是疯狂
This is madness.
我以为你是这儿的领袖，杜酷
I thought you were the leader here, Dooku.
这件事与我无关
This had nothing to do with me, I assure you.
我会立刻申请释放你
I will petition immediately to have you set free.
希望快一点，我有任务在身
Well, I hope it doesn't take too long. I have work to do.
容我请问为何绝地武士...
May I ask why a Jedi knight...
大老远来到吉诺西斯？
is all the way out here on Geonosis?
我追踪赏金猎人强格费特到此
I've been tracking a bounty hunter named Jango Fett.
你认识他吗？
Do you know him?
此地没有赏金猎人
There are no bounty hunters here that I am aware of.
吉诺西斯人不信任他们
The Geonosians don't trust them.
话是没错，但他确实在这里
Who can blame them? But he is here, I can assure you.
可惜我们未曾谋面，欧比王
It's a great pity our paths have never crossed before, Obi-Wan.
金魁刚非常赞赏你
Qui-Gon always spoke very highly of you.
真希望他还活在世上
I wish he were still alive.
此刻正需要他的协助
I could use his help right now.
金魁刚不会与你为伍
Qui-Gon Jinn would never join you.
话不要说太满，年轻绝地武士
Don't be so sure, my young Jedi.
他曾经是我的徒弟
You forget that he was once my apprentice...
正如你是他的徒弟
just as you were once his.
他知道参议院的腐败...
He knew all about the corruption in the senate...
但如果他知道实情的话...
but he wouldn't have gone along with it
他就不会坐视不管
if he had learned the truth as I have.
实情？
- The truth?
是的，实情
- The truth.
你相不相信，共和国根本...
What if I told you that the Republic was now under the control...
在西斯黑暗大帝的掌握下？
of the dark lord of the Sith?
不可能，绝地武士会知道
No, that's not possible. TheJedi would be aware of it.
黑暗势力蒙蔽了他们，朋友
The dark side of the Force has clouded their vision, my friend.
数百位参议员已经在...
Hundreds of senators are now under the influence...
黑暗大帝达斯西帝的掌控中
of a Sith lord called Darth Sidious.
我不相信
I don't believe you.
贸易联盟总督...
The viceroy of the Trade Federation...
曾经跟达斯西帝结盟
was once in league with this Darth Sidious...
但十年前遭黑暗大帝背叛
but he was betrayed ten years ago by the dark lord.
他向我求助并说出实情
He came to me for help. He told me everything.
你一定要加入我，欧比王
You must join me, Obi-Wan...
合力打倒西斯！
and together we will destroy the Sith!
我绝不会加入你，杜酷
I will never join you, Dooku.
或许释放你会有些困难
It may be difficult to secure your release.
显然分离主义者...
It's-a clear desa separatists made a pact...
跟贸易联盟已达成协定
wesa desa Federation du Trade.
参议员同事们
Senators, ''dellow felagates'':
为因应共和国的燃眉之急...
In response to this direct threat to the Republic...
我向本议会提案...
mesa propose that the senate...
即刻将紧急处分权...
give immediately emergency powers...
赋予最高议会议长
to the supreme chancellor.
白卜庭！白卜庭！白卜庭！
Palpatine! Palpatine!
肃静！保持肃静！
Order! We shall have order!
我心中极为不愿意...
It is with great reluctance...
同意此项授命
that I have agreed to this calling.
我热爱民主
I love democracy.
我爱共和国
I love the Republic.
各位今日赋予我的权力...
The power you give me...
危机消除后我会立刻放弃
I will lay down when this crisis has abated.
我接受授权后的第一项法令...
And as my first act with this new authority...
即是为共和国建立强大的军队
I will create a grand army of the Republic...
抵御日益强大的分离主义威胁
to counter the increasing threats of the separatists.
建军已成定案
It is done, then.
我带领全数绝地武士
I will take whatJedi we have left
前往吉诺西斯帮欧比王
and go to Geonosis and help Obi-Wan.
我将前往卡密诺星察看...
Visit I will the cloners on Kamino...
共和国所订制的复制人大军
and see this army they have created for the Republic.
看到那些排气孔吗？
See those columns of steam straight ahead?
应该是某种废气
They're exhaust vents of some type.
那儿可以降落
That'll do.
不管发生什么事都听我的
Look, whatever happens out there, follow my lead.
我不想搅入战局
I'm not interested in getting into a war here.
身为参议员，说不定我可以...
As a member of the senate...
透过外交途径解决目前的乱局
maybe I can find a diplomatic solution to this mess.
不用担心，我不会再跟你争辩
Don't worry. I've given up trying to argue with you.
笨小朋友，如果需要帮忙...
My obtuse little friend, if they had needed our help...
他们自然会开口
they would have asked for it.
你要多学学人类的行为模式
You obviously have a great deal to learn about human behavior.
身为技工，你想太多了
For a mechanic, you seem to do an excessive amount of thinking.
我的专长程式正是了解人类！
I am programmed to understand humans!
“什么意思？”意思是我是老大
''What does that mean?'' That means I am in charge here!
你做什么？外面状况不明 难道你都没有感觉吗？
Where are you going now? You don't know what's out there. Have you no sense at all?
白痴！
Idiot!
请等一下
Please wait.
你知不知道你要去哪里？
Do you know where you're going?
等一下
Wait.
啊，天啊...噢！
噢，老天啊！
Oh, my goodness!
谁来帮我关机！
Shut me down!
机器正在制造机器
Machines making machines.
真变态
How perverse!
慢点，R2！
Calm down, R2!
我差点儿摔下去
I almost fell.
等一下会有机会，所以...
You'll get your chance--
我变成废铁了
I'm scrap.
恶梦一场！
It's a nightmare!
我要回家！
I want to go home!
我有做错什么事吗？
What did I do to deserve this?
不晓得可怜的R2怎么样了？
I wonder what happened to poor little R2.
他老是惹麻烦
He's always getting himself into trouble.
哦，不要！
Oh, no!
我都弄糊涂了
I'm so confused.
又来了，欧比王这次会杀了我
Not again! Obi-Wan's gonna kill me.
别动，绝地武士！把他们带走
Don't move,Jedi! Take him away.
不要怕
Don't be afraid.
我不怕死
I'm not afraid to die.
从你进到我的生命开始...
I've been dying a little bit each day
我就一天天逐渐枯萎
since you came back into my life.
你说这话是什么意思？
What are you talking about?
我爱你
I love you.
你爱我？
You love me?
我以为我们决定不能相爱
I thought we had decided not to fall in love...
因为我们会被迫活在谎言中
that we would be forced to live a lie...
因为会摧毁我们的生活
and that it would destroy our lives.
反正我们的生活终归会被摧毁
I think our lives are about to be destroyed anyway.
我真的深深的爱著你
I truly... deeply love you...
在我们死前，我要你知道
and before we die, I want you to know.
我正怀疑你是否收到我的讯息
I was beginning to wonder if you'd got my message.
我按照你的吩咐转传至科罗森
I retransmitted it just as you had requested, Master.
然后决定前来救你
Then we decided to come and rescue you.
干得好
Good job.
稍安勿躁，稍安勿躁
Settle down. Settle down.
开始行刑
Let the executions begin.
我有个很坏的预感
I've got a bad feeling about this.
放轻松，专注心思
-Just relax. Concentrate.
帕米怎么办？
- What about Padme?
看来她已经脱身了
She seems to be on top of things.
她犯规！射她，或想个办法！
She can't do that! Shoot her... or something!
跳！
Jump!
状况不对劲了！强格！
This isn't how it's supposed to be!
把她干掉！
Jango! Finish her off!
耐心，总督，她死定了
Patience, Viceroy, patience. She will die.
云杜大师...
Master Windu.
欢迎你也加入
How pleasant of you to join us.
闹剧该收场了
This party's over.
勇敢...但愚蠢，老朋友
Brave... but foolish, my old Jedi friend.
你们人真是少得可怜
You're impossibly outnumbered.
我可不这么认为
I don't think so.
走著瞧
We'll see.
腿不能动，我需要保养了
My legs aren't moving. I must need maintenance.
怎么这么吵？打仗！
What's all this noise? A battle!
搞错了！我的内建程式是礼宾
There's been some terrible mistake!I'm programmed for etiquette,
不是搞破坏！
not destruction!
去死，绝地狗杂种！
Die,Jedi dogs!
噢！我在说什么？
Oh! What did I say?
天啊，真是抱歉到了极点
Oh, dear. I'm terribly sorry about all this.
抱歉，我被绊住了，起不来
Excuse me. I'm trapped. I can't get up.
你说这叫...外交解决途径？
- You call this a diplomatic solution?
不...这叫激烈的争辩
- No, I call it aggressive negotiations.
收到，收到
- Uh-oh. - Roger, roger.
R2，你在这做什么？
R2, what are you doing here?
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
住手！你会扯断...我的脖子！
Stop that! You're going to strain something. My neck!
噢，你要带我去哪里？
Now where are you taking me?
不要拖那么用力
This is such a drag!
我真是丈二金刚摸不著头绪
I'm quite beside myself.
R2，拜托小心点
R2, please be careful!
我快短路了
You're singeing my circuits!
好！头有接正吗？
Yes, but is my head on straight?
云杜大师...
Master Windu...
果然是一代豪侠
you have fought gallantly...
该当名留绝地圣殿
worthy of recognition in the archives of theJedi order.
现在...你的时候到了
Now... it is finished.
投降...我还可以饶你一命
Surrender... and your lives will be spared.
我们不是用来交换条件的人质
We will not be hostages to be bartered, Dooku!
既然如此...抱歉啦，老朋友
Then... I'm sorry, old friend.
看！
Look!
生存者四周形成了个包围阵地
Around the survivors a perimeter create.
我作了个非常奇怪的梦
I've had the most peculiar dream!
万一杜酷逃走...
If Dooku escapes...
他会号召更多星系叛变
rally more systems to his cause he will.
抓好！
Hold on!
瞄准能源供应器正上方！
Aim right above the fuel cells!
非常犀利，小徒弟
Good call, my young Padawan.
绝地武士召集了一支大军
TheJedi have amassed a huge army.
怎么可能
That doesn't seem possible.
这么短的时间怎么建军？
How could theJedi come up with an army so quickly?
全部机器人都送上战场
We must send all available droids into battle.
敌军排山倒海而来
There are too many.
所有通讯都受到干扰不通
Our communications have been jammed.
飞行员，降落在集合区！
Pilot, land in that assembly area!
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
长官，我有五支突袭队...
Sir...I have five special commando units
等待您下令，长官
awaiting your orders, sir.
带我到前进指挥中心
To the forward command center take me.
攻击联盟战舰，快！
Attack those Federation starships, quickly!
尤达大师，前线部队不断挺进
Master Yoda, all forward positions are advancing.
很好，非常好
Very good. Very good.
战况越来越不利
This is not looking good at all!
我方战舰要退回太空中
We must get the starships back into space.
非下令撤退不可
We have to order a retreat.
我师父不会轻松放过...
My master will never allow the Republic...
共和国这次的叛变行动
to get away with this treachery.
我要让战士们躲进地下墓穴
I'm sending my warriors to hide in the catacombs.
终极武器设计图...
TheJedi must not find
绝不能让绝地武士发现
our designs for the ultimate weapon.
计划若曝光，我们就完了
If they find out what we are planning to build, we're doomed.
我带设计图到科罗森去
I will take the designs with me to Coruscant.
跟我师父在一起安全多了
They will be much safer there with my master.
将火力集中在最近的战舰
Concentrate all your fire on the nearest starship.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
所有象限仪调至5-1-5区
Move all quadrants to sector 51 5.
看那边！
Look over there!
是杜酷，把他打下来！
It's Dooku! Shoot him down!
没有飞弹了，长官
We're out of rockets, sir.
跟著他！
- Follow him!
我们需要援兵！
- We're gonna need some help!
没有时间！
There isn't time!
安纳金和我可以应付
Anakin and I can handle this!
帕米！
降落！
Put the ship down!
安纳金！
Anakin
大敌当前怎能儿女情长！
Don't let your personal feelings get in the way!
跟紧那辆飞行机车！
Follow that speeder!
降下去！
- Lower the ship!
我一个人对付不了杜酷！
- I can't take Dooku alone!
我需要你帮忙
I need you! If we catch him,
逮到他，战争立刻就结束了！
we can end this war right now!
我们有要务在身！
- We have a job to do!
我管不了那么多！降落！
- I don't care! Put the ship down!
你会被逐出绝地武士行列！
You will be expelled from theJedi order!
我不能丢下她
- I can't leave her!
冷静想想
- Come to your senses!
如果帕米是你，她会怎么做
What do you think Padme would do were she in your position?
她会尽她应尽的义务
She would do her duty.
机器人军队全面撤退了
The droid army is in full retreat.
很好，司令官
Well done, Commander.
找艘太空船给我
Bring me a ship.
该为你今天杀害的...
You're gonna pay for all theJedi
绝地武士偿命了，杜酷
that you killed today, Dooku.
一起攻击，你慢慢从...
We'll take him together.
不，我现在就杀了他！ 不，安纳金！不！
- I'm taking him now! - No, Anakin! No!
不要！
No!
看到了吧，我的力量远超过你
As you see, myJedi powers are far beyond yours.
还不退下？
Now... back down.
碍难照办
I don't think so.
肯诺比大师，你真叫我失望
Master Kenobi, you disappoint me.
枉费尤达那么推崇你
Yoda holds you in such high esteem.
本事不过如此
Surely you can do better.
你还好吧？
Are you all right?
还好
Uh-huh.
赶快回前进指挥中心去
We'd better get back to the forward command center.
不，不
No.
集结你所有的部队
Gather what troops you can.
我们得赶去那座停机中心
We've got to get to that hangar.
找艘运输工具，快！
Get a transport. Hurry!
立刻照办
Right away.
很勇敢哦，小男孩
Brave of you, boy.
但，我以为你学聪明了
But I would have thought you had learned your lesson.
我一向学得比较慢
I am a slow learner.
安纳金！
Anakin
尤达大师
Master Yoda.
杜酷伯爵
Count Dooku.
这是你最后一次干涉我们的事
You have interfered with our affairs for the last time.
你的力量变强了，杜酷
Powerful you have become, Dooku.
我感觉到你体内的黑暗势力
The dark side I sense in you.
我比任何绝地武士都强
I've become more powerful than anyJedi.
即使是你
Even you.
你该学的还多著呢
Much to learn you still have.
显然，我们无法用...
It is obvious that this contest cannot be decided...
对原力的见解分高下
by our knowledge of the Force...
那只好用剑术决胜负了
but by our skills with a lightsaber.
技术还不错，老徒弟
Fought well you have, my old Padawan.
才刚开始呢
This is just the beginning.
原力与我们同在，西帝大师
The Force is with us, Master Sidious.
欢迎归来，提拉诺斯大公
Welcome home, Lord Tyranus.
做得非常好
You have done well.
我有个好消息，大帝
I have good news for you, my lord.
战争已经开始了
- The war has begun. - Excellent.
完美，一切按照计划进行
Everything is going as planned.
你相信杜酷伯爵说的话吗？
Do you believe what Count Dooku said
他说西帝已经掌控了参议院
about Sidious controlling the senate?
我总感觉不对劲
It doesn't feel right.
杜酷已经加入黑暗势力
Joined the dark side Dooku has.
谎言，欺骗...
Lies, deceit...
制造猜忌是他的拿手好戏
creating mistrust are his ways now.
话虽如此...
Nevertheless..
我们最好还是多留意参议院
I feel we should keep a closer eye on the senate.
我同意
I agree.
你徒弟呢？
Where is your apprentice?
护送艾米达拉议员回那卜星
On his way to Naboo, escorting Senator Amidala home.
没有复制人，我们真的赢不了
I have to admit that without the clones, it would not have been a victory.
赢？
Victory?
你说赢吗，欧比王大师？
Victory, you say?Master Obi-Wan,
这不是胜利
not victory.
黑暗势力的裹尸布已被掀开
The shroud of the dark side has fallen.
复制人大战才刚开始呢
Begun the Clone War has.